Inventory of the Roger Mansell collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Roger Mansell collection
1919-2010
2001C48
Hoover Institution Archives
35 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 3 sound discs (18.5 linear feet)
The collection consists of materials collected by Roger Mansell during the course of his research for his publication Captured: The Forgotten Men of Guam, as well as his role as director of the Center for Research of Allied POWs under the Japanese and its corresponding online database, http://www.mansell.com. Included in these materials are memoirs, diaries, photocopies of government documents, rosters, interview transcripts, correspondence, maps, sketches, notes, printed matter, photographs, electronic records, videorecordings, memorabilia, and sound recordings detailing the experience of prisoners of war held in Japan, the Philippines, Guam, Taiwan, Singapore, and Netherlands East Indies during World War II.
Mansell, Roger
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2001.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Location of Originals
The collection includes many photocopies and digital copies of government documents permanently housed at different archival repositories in the United States, Australia, and elsewhere. Photocopies of diaries and correspondence, as well as original memoirs and personal narratives, were given to Mansell from the personal collections of former POWs and their families.
Separated Materials
Most monographs have been transferred to the Hoover Institution Library and can be found in the catalog using the subject term "Mansell Coll."
Related Materials
Marie Adams papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Richard A. Arvidson diary, Hoover Institution Archives
Leon Grove memoir, Hoover Institution Archives
Sheldon H. Harris papers, Hoover Institution Archives
William Henry Hastings papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Geoffrey Monument papers, Hoover Institution Archives
George C. Mora papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Alan Asbury O'Guinn papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Santo Tomás Internment Camp, January 4, 1942 to September 27, 1943: typescript, Hoover Institution Archives
Katherine Ream Sobeck papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Wendell Wilcox diary, Hoover Institution Archives
Harold N. Wilson papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
1935 October 8 Born, Brooklyn, New York
1953-1959 Attended Brown University
1959-1962 Served in U.S. Army, stationed in Korea and Fort Bliss, Texas
1960s-1970s Founder, Mansell Advertising, Mansell Graphics, and Mansell Publishing
1990s Began researching prisoners-of-war of the Japanese in World War II
Founder, the Center for Research Allied POWs Under the Japanese, Los Altos, California
Late 1990s Publisher, Tameme, nonprofit bilingual literary journal
2006 Spoke at International Research FEPOW History Conference in Alrewas, United Kingdom
2008 Fellow at University of Shenyang Research Center on World War II POWs
2010 October 25 Died, Palo Alto, California
2012 Author, Captured: The Forgotten Men of Guam, edited by Linda Goetz Holmes, published posthumously
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection consists of materials collected by Roger Mansell during the course of his research for his publication Captured: The Forgotten Men of Guam, as well as his role as director of the Center for Research of Allied POWs Under the Japanese and its corresponding online database, www.mansell.com. Included in these materials are memoirs, diaries, photocopies of government documents, rosters, interview transcripts, correspondence, maps, sketches, notes, printed matter, photographs, electronic records, videorecordings, memorabilia, and sound recordings detailing the experience of POWs based in Japan, the Philippines, Guam, Taiwan, Singapore, and Netherlands East Indies during World War II.
The materials reflect years of research devoted to documenting the fates of prisoners-of-war (POWs) in the Pacific theater of World War II. For this reason, the countless photocopies of government documents obtained from the National Archives and former POWs were cross-referenced by Mansell and his team with information gathered from correspondence and firsthand interviews, resulting in a detailed account of enlisted men, nurses, and civilians interned in the Pacific during World War II. Some files in the register include two date ranges, accounting both for the original documents (or photocopies) and Mansell's research notes and email correspondence.
The collection is arranged into series based on subject and physical format, as defined by Mansell. Research on individual POWs appears in the Prisoner-of-War File. The files are arranged in alphabetical order by the name of the former POW being researched by Mansell and not by the name of the actual person of contact, although in many cases these names are the same. Also included in this series are Mansell's records from interviews with POWs and printed materials collected from organizations of former POWs.
Research materials on Prisoner-of-War Camps in Japan and Prisoner-of-War Camps Outside Japan make up the majority of the collection. Documents in these series are similar to those in other parts of the collection, but focus more on the detailed experiences of POWs within individual camps. Maps and sketches provide understanding of the layout of each camp, while personal narratives of POWs and reports by government offices, including the United States Office of War Crimes, fill in details about treatment by Japanese guards, diet, living arrangements, and disease. Among these materials are Mansell's email correspondence and notes, highlighting corrections, clarifications, and areas of interest.
Documentation from civilians interned at camps in Japan and the Philippines appear in the Civilian Prisoner-of-War Camps series. Included among these research materials is an apron from Santo Tomás Internment Camp, with the embroidered signatures of over 100 internees, and a hand colored map of Manila.
The Combat Units' Rosters and Reports series contains materials from U.S. and Australian combat units stationed in the Pacific, particularly in the Philippines, during World War II. It consists mainly of photocopies of records from the National Archives, as well as original spreadsheets created by Mansell and colleagues during the course of their research. The series also includes original writings by POWs, including memoirs and personal narratives.
The collection includes a large number of electronic media in the form of compact discs, floppy disks, and DVDs containing digitized photographs, films, interview notes, rosters, and scans of original documents. These materials are interfiled with corresponding paper records. Some folders in the collection contain printed copies of these records in their entirety, while others do not. In addition, some of these records are included in the Center for Research of Allied POWs Under the Japanese POW camp database, available online at http://www.mansell.com.
The researcher should be aware that Roger Mansell also donated original materials he collected from Geoffrey Monument and George C. Mora, which are now cataloged separately in their own collections at the Hoover Institution Archives.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into the following series based on original order: Prisoner-of-War File, Prisoner-of-War Camps in Japan File, Prisoner-of-War Camps Outside Japan File, Civilian Prisoner-of-War Camps File, Combat Units' Rosters and Reports, General Research File, Videorecordings, and Sound Recordings.
Concentration camps.; Philippines--History--Japanese occupation, 1942-1945.; Prisoner-of-war camps--Japan.; Prisoners of war.; Santo Tomas Interment Camp (Manila, Philippines).; Video tapes.; World War, 1939-1945--Concentration camps.; World War, 1939-1945--Japan.; World War, 1939-1945--Philippines.; World War, 1939-1945--Prisoners and prisons.
- Prisoner-of-War File, 1919-2010, undated (Boxes 1-9)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes research materials in the form of memoirs, diaries, personal narratives, correspondence, memoranda, interview transcripts, photographs, printed matter, and electronic records. Arranged in the following groups, according to original order: Alphabetic name file, individuals; interview notes and related correspondence; and organizations of former POWs. Materials from individual POWs and interviews are arranged alphabetically by last name, and organizations of former POWs are arranged by physical form.
  - Alphabetic name files, individuals, 1919-1948, 1971-2010 (Boxes 1-6)
    - General (Folder 1: 1)
    - Adair, William G., 1971, 2004, undated (Folder 1: 2-3)
    - Ames, Godfrey R., 1930-1944, 1985-1989 (Folder 1: 4-6)
    - Arvidson, Richard A., 2008 (Folder 1: 7)
      Includes Mansell's notes on Arvidson's diary at Hoover Institution Archives.
    - Barker, Robert Alois, 1990 (Folder 1: 8)
    - Barwick, Idris James, 2005 (Folder 1: 9)
    - Benini, Alcide (or Aleido), 1940-1941, 1985 (Folder 1: 10-11)
    - Berry, Frederick Langwith, 2007 (Folder 1: 12)
    - Bevolden, Chet, 1996, undated (Folder 1: 13)
    - Bjoring, Robert George, 1996 (Folder 1: 14)
      Includes two 3.5-inch floppy disks containing Bjoring's memoir titled "A 1920 Baby" (5 chapters totaling 236 pages; includes multiple versions of some chapters). Use copies available in reading room.
    - Boyington, Gregory, 1988 (Folder 1: 15)
    - Brown, Jim, 1999, 2003 (Folder 1: 16)
    - Brown, Joseph Rust, 1982-2007 (Folder 1: 17-20)
      Includes his memoir We Stole to Live, Zentsuji Cookbook, newsletters, and correspondence.
    - Bulford, Alexander, 1940s (Folder 2: 1)
    - Chambliss, Jesse Royce, 1946-1947 (Folder 2: 2)
    - Charles, Myron W., 2002 (Folder 2: 3)
    - Church, Ray H., 1941-2000s (Folder 2: 4)
    - Cornell, Theodore M., Col., 2003, undated (Folder 2: 5-6)
    - Cowan, James H., 1970, 2002 (Folder 2: 7-8)
      Includes manuscript titled "Bataan: A Survivor's Memoir" and related correspondence. See also Box 23 for updated version containing photographs supplied by Mansell.
    - Duffy, George W., undated (Folder 2: 9)
    - Dunn, Garth, 2000-2006 (Folder 2: 10-11)
    - Dunne, Joseph B., 1944-1945 (Folder 2: 12)
    - Edsall, Carlton, 1942-1946 (Folder 2: 13)
    - Ely, Thomas George, 1999 (Folder 2: 14)
    - Fortier, Malcolm Vaughn, 1946 (Folder 2: 15)
      Includes illustrated memoir titled Life of a P.O.W. Under the Japanese: In Caricature.
    - Gamble, Bruce, 2000s (Folder 2: 16)
    - Hale, Edward E., 1945, 2001 (Folder 2: 17-18)
    - Hamilton, Stuart, Col., 1942-1946, 2009 (Folder 2: 19)
      One compact disc containing a copy of "Activities Chemical Warfare Service Philippine Islands WWII," 1946; Col. Hamilton's personal diary from POW camp; and photographs of Hamilton in military uniform.
    - Harris, Sheldon, circa 2008, undated (Folder 2: 20)
      Includes Mansell's notes on Harris collection at Hoover Institution Archives.
    - Harty, Kevin Denis, 1945 (Folder 2: 21)
    - Hays, Roy Edgar, undated (Folder 2: 22)
    - Hollering, Martinus, circa 1945, 2008 (Folder 2: 23)
    - Jaeggli, John Lewis, 2009 (Folder 2: 24)
      Includes transcript of oral history recorded in 1983.
    - Johnson, Joseph Q., 1945-1946, 2001 (Folder 2: 25)
    - Johnson, W. C., circa 2008 (Folder 3: 1)
      One compact disc.
    - Kay, Logan, circa 1971 (Folder 3: 2)
    - Kirk, Terence S., 1942, 2003 (Folder 3: 3-4)
      Includes printed photographs and one compact disc of photographs and writings relating to Kirk's book The Secret Camera.
    - Langton, H. H., 1944 (Folder 3: 5)
    - Langworthy, Burton, 1982-1995 (Folder 3: 6)
      One compact disc of photographs.
    - Leaming, Jack, 1944, 2000-2002 (Folder 3: 7)
    - Lovering, L., 2005 (Folder 3: 8)
    - MacIntosh, Jim, 1941-1999 (Folder 3: 9-12)
    - Magelssen, Sverre Walter, 1919-1942, 1989-2005 (Folder 3: 13)
    - Marks, Mortimer, undated (Folder 3: 14-16)
      Includes personal narrative titled "Zentsuji: Before, During, and After World War II" with scrapbook addendum of original photographs. Also includes eleven compact discs containing digital scans of photographs from Marks' personal narrative.
    - Mazzaral, Bert, 1940-1999 (Folder 4: 1)
      Two 3.5-inch floppy disks containing transcripts of war diary.
    - McCamley, Joseph, undated (Folder 4: 2)
    - McKasson, William, 2003 (Folder 4: 3)
    - Meyers, A. W., 1941-1945 (Folder 4: 4)
    - Miller, James, 1946-1947 (Folder 4: 5)
    - Montoya, Carlos and Tony, 2003 (Folder 4: 6)
    - Monument, Geoffrey, 1948-1997 (Folder 4: 7-8)
    - Mora, George C., 1941-1945, 1999 (Folder 4: 9)
      Two 3.5-inch floppy disks.
    - Murphy, James, undated (Folder 4: 10)
    - Myers, Larry "Lee,", undated (Folder 4: 11)
    - Palmer, George, 2010 (Folder 4: 12-13)
    - Parazo, Menandro, 2009 (Folder 4: 14)
    - Penniger, William R., 2002 (Folder 4: 15)
    - Peters, Joseph Franklin, undated (Folder 4: 16)
    - Petrie, Wayne Joseph, undated (Folder 5: 1)
    - Pickett, Ernest, 2002-2003 (Folder 5: 2)
    - Reynolds, Roberts, undated (Folder 5: 3)
    - Richardson, Frank Lloyd, circa 1943-1945 (Folder 5: 4)
    - Robertson Jr., Gordon Bennett, 2000-2003 (Folder 5: 5-8)
    - Roslansky, Martin, undated (Folder 5: 9)
      See also: Sound Recordings.
    - Rushing, Jim, 1997 (Folder 5: 10)
    - Saunders, Cecil, 1945 October (Folder 5: 11)
    - Smith, Warren "Bill,", 1992 (Folder 5: 12)
    - Sterner, Joseph A., 1999 (Folder 5: 13)
    - Sullivan, J. M., undated (Folder 5: 14)
    - Ushakoff, Michael M., 1945, 2004 (Folder 5: 15)
    - Van Peenan, H. J., undated (Folder 5: 16)
    - Wagner, Boyd D. "Buzz", 2006 (Folder 5: 17)
    - Walker, Dorsey B., 1944-1958 (Folder 5: 18)
    - Weiss, Charles Franklin, 2010 (Folder 5: 19)
    - Whittenberg, Woodrow "Woody" Wilson, 2010 (Folder 5: 20)
      Includes correspondence, notes, and one DVD containing a filmed oral history interview of Whittenberg.
    - Wilson, Harold (Folder 5: 21-23)
      - Clippings, 1940 (Folder 5: 21)
      - Correspondence, 1942-1945, 2008 (Folder 5: 22)
      - Invitations, 1928-1939 (Folder 5: 23)
    - Wilson, Henry S., 1942-1945, 2009 (Folder 6: 1-2)
    - Witts, David A., circa 2000-2004 (Folder 6: 3-8)
    - Wright, William "Cowboy,", undated (Folder 6: 9)
    - Yardley, Richard, 2003 (Folder 6: 10)
  - Interview notes and related correspondence, 1940s-2007, undated (Boxes 6-9)
    - General, undated (Folder 6: 11-12)
      Notebook and interview questions.
    - Agnes, Francis, 1943-2001, undated (Folder 6: 13)
      20th Pursuit, Bataan, Hirohata.
    - Arciaga, F., 1936-1939, 1990 (Folder 6: 14)
    - Baggett, Ralph (Folder 6: 15-19)
      - Correspondence, 2000-2001 (Folder 6: 15-16)
      - Writings, undated (Folder 6: 17)
      - Writings by Mansell, circa 2000, undated (Folder 6: 18)
      - Notes, 2000-2001 (Folder 6: 19)
    - Barnett, Carroll D. "Barney,", 1995-2001 (Folder 7: 1-2)
    - du Berrier, Hilaire, 2001 (Folder 7: 3)
    - Bjoring, Robert G., 1996, 2000 (Folder 7: 4)
      Notes from interviews and one 3.5-inch floppy disk. This disk duplicates the contents of those in box 1, folder 14, containing Bjoring's memoir titled "A 1920 Baby" (5 chapters totaling 236 pages; includes multiple versions of some chapters). Use copies available in reading room.
    - Blackman, William Harry, 2000 (Folder 7: 5)
      Royal Australian Air Force.
    - Bowman, Leroy, 2000, undated (Folder 7: 6)
    - Burkhart, Thomas Francis, 2001-2002 (Folder 7: 7)
      45th Infantry, Bataan, Tanagawa, Zentsuji.
    - Carney, Frank J., 1947, 2001 (Folder 7: 8)
    - Chittenden, William H., 1940, 2001-2002 (Folder 7: 9)
      North China Marines.
    - Cobb, George, 1999-2000 (Folder 7: 10)
      Corregidor, Bilibid, Manina Docks, Noto Maru, Hanawa.
    - Cope, Ray, circa 2002 (Folder 7: 11)
      Civilian contractor on Wake Island. One 3.5-inch floppy disk.
    - Copeland, Robert E., 1945, 2002 (Folder 7: 12-13)
      Includes photocopy of diary and clippings from Hoover Institution Archives.
    - Dodge, Bernard, circa 1942 (Folder 7: 14)
    - Dunn, Garth (Folder 7: 15-17)
      - Correspondence, 2000-2002 (Folder 7: 15)
      - Writings and memoranda by Mansell, 2000 (Folder 7: 16)
      - Maps, rosters, and reports, undated (Folder 7: 17)
    - Epperson, Robert, 2000 (Folder 7: 18)
    - Fero (Romero), Joseph F., 2000 (Folder 7: 19)
      Bataan to Hirohata.
    - Ford, John, undated (Folder 7: 20)
      See also: Franken, John.
    - Franken, John, 1998-2001 (Folder 7: 21)
      See also: Ford, John.
    - Frederick, Revice N., 2002 (Folder 7: 22)
      USMC, Guam, Sumay, Hirohata.
    - Gallagher, Frank, 1999-2000 (Folder 7: 23)
    - Glover, Roy Scott, 2001 (Folder 7: 24)
    - Graham, Clarence M. "Cal,", 1992, 2002 (Folder 7: 25)
      Corregidor, Fukuoka no. 17.
    - Green, Smith "Smitty" L., 1943, 2002 (Folder 7: 26)
    - Gross, Franklin David, 1945, 2003 (Folder 7: 27)
      Wake Island, Woosung, Kiangwan, Tsumori, Rokuroshi.
    - Hale, Edward E., circa 1941, 1999 (Folder 7: 28-29)
    - Halle, Keith A., 2000-2001 (Folder 7: 30)
    - Halloran, Ray "Hap,", 1944-1945, 1990-2001 (Folder 7: 31-32)
    - Harris, Chuck, 2000-2001 (Folder 7: 33)
    - Hamby, Thornton, 2001 (Folder 7: 34)
    - Harper, Raymond J., 2003-2007 (Folder 7: 35)
      One DVD containing a filmed oral history interview of Harper.
    - Harrington, Wilson Hempfield, 1942-1948, 2000 (Folder 7: 36)
    - Hober, Wouter, 2000-2001, undated (Folder 7: 37)
    - Holm, Holger L., 2002 (Folder 8: 1)
      One compact disc containing Holm's diary, photographs from Funatsu camp, and links to websites.
    - Honan, Thomas R., 1940s, 1996-2001 (Folder 8: 2-4)
      Includes photocopies of aerial photographs, sketches of camp, personal narrative, and memoranda re interview.
    - Hoskins, John "Jack,", circa 2002 (Folder 8: 5)
      Two compact discs and one 3.5-inch floppy disk.
    - Humphrey, Herbert, 1944, 1988-2001, undated (Folder 8: 6-7)
      Pfc., Sumay, Guam, Zentsuji, Osaka.
    - Ianerelli, Jean, 2000-2002 (Folder 8: 8)
    - Irwin, Ernest, 2000 (Folder 8: 9)
    - Jackson, Leona, 2000 (Folder 8: 10)
      Nurse in POW camp.
    - Joslin, Harold E., 2002 (Folder 8: 11)
    - Kerns, Jim, 2001 (Folder 8: 12)
      Two compact discs of photographs from Kamioka camp and Nagoya detachment camp.
    - LaGrone, Harry J., 2000-2001 (Folder 8: 13)
    - Larson, Alf, 2004 (Folder 8: 14)
    - Leaming, Jack, 2002 (Folder 8: 15)
    - Lyles, John Henry, 1942-1945, 2002 (Folder 8: 16)
    - Marks, Mortimer, 2000-2001 (Folder 8: 17)
    - Martin, Max, 2000 (Folder 8: 18)
    - McElfish, Roy E., 1945, 2002 (Folder 8: 19)
      POW at Corregidor and Umedo. One compact disc of photographs from Rokuroshi and Zentsuji.
    - Menzies, Michael, 1940s, 2000-2001 (Folder 8: 20-21)
    - Metzler, P. G., 1964 (Folder 8: 22)
      One compact disc. Printed copy available in folder.
    - Miller, Albert E., 2000 (Folder 8: 23)
    - Morgan, Dean, 2000-2001 (Folder 8: 24)
    - Morin, Ben, undated (Folder 9: 1)
    - Ross, Howard D. "Seagull,", 1942, 2002 (Folder 9: 2)
      Three compact discs containing photographs from Zentsuji.
    - Seymour, Charles R., 2001 (Folder 9: 3)
    - Small, George, 2001 (Folder 9: 4)
    - Steiger, George, 2002 (Folder 9: 5)
    - Sterling, Warren C., undated (Folder 9: 6)
    - Todd, G. S. (Folder 9: 7-9)
      - Correspondence, 2000 (Folder 9: 7)
      - Interview questions and notes, 2000 (Folder 9: 8)
      - Maps and drawings, circa 1942 (Folder 9: 9)
        Photocopies.
    - Walker, Dorsey, 2002 (Folder 9: 10)
      One 3.5-inch floppy disk of photographs.
    - Wallace, S. R., 1940s (Folder 9: 11)
    - Ward, Bob, 2008 (Folder 9: 12)
  - Organizations of former POWs, 1999-2009 (Box 9)
    - Materials from conventions, conferences, and memorials (Folder 9: 13-18)
      - 62nd and 63rd National Convention of American Defenders of Bataan and Corregidor (ADBC), 2007-2008 (Folder 9: 13)
        Brochure and flyers.
      - Center for Internee Rights, 2000 (Folder 9: 14)
        Flyer.
      - Far East Prisoners of War (FEPOW), 2003-2005 (Folder 9: 15)
        Newsletter and correspondence.
      - Millville Area Veterans' Memorial, 2004 (Folder 9: 16)
        Flyers and correspondence.
      - Researching Far East Prisoners of War History Conference, London, 2006 (Folder 9: 17-18)
    - Newsletters (Folder 9: 19-27)
      - Barbed Wire and Bamboo, Ex-Prisoners of War Association of Australia, 1999-2002, 2008 (Folder 9: 19)
      - Benjo News: 'J' Force, Kobe House and Hakensho, 2001-2004 (Folder 9: 20)
      - Beyond the Wire, Bay Area Civilian Ex-Prisoners of War (BACEPOW), 2009 January (Folder 9: 21)
      - Focus: Ax-POWs Wives and Widows, 1999-2002 (Folder 9: 22)
        Includes related correspondence and clippings.
      - Internee Affairs, 2000 (Folder 9: 23)
      - News Bulletin, Ex-Prisoners of War and Relatives' Association, Australia, 1999 (Folder 9: 24)
      - Nimitz News, 2000 (Folder 9: 25)
      - The Quan, 2002-2009 (Folder 9: 26-27)
    - Materials from reunions (Folder 9: 28-35)
      - Manila Liberation, San Antonio, 2002 (Folder 9: 28)
      - U.S. Navy Asiatic Fleet, 2004 (Folder 9: 29)
      - Zentsuji (Albuquerque, New Mexico), 2000 (Folder 9: 30-32)
      - Zentsuji (Kansas City, Missouri), 2001 (Folder 9: 33-35)
- Prisoner-of-War Camps in Japan File, 1940-1947, 1978-2007 (Boxes 10-17, 36)
  Includes research materials in the form of photocopies of rosters, government documents, diaries, memoirs, maps, sketches, notes, and photographs; interview notes, correspondence, and electronic records. Most original titles were maintained, though folders with similar titles have been grouped together to aid research.
  The subseries are arranged alphabetically by geographical location. Camps that are identified by number are arranged in numerical order. Specific locations of camps, when known, are provided as a parenthetical note after the camp number. Files relating to individual internees are listed alphabetically at the end of each subseries.
  - General lists, 1940s-1945, 2001 (Box 10)
    - POW camps in Japan, alphabetical, 1944-1945 (Folder 10: 1-4)
      Photocopies of government documents.
    - British deceased personnel in South Japan, 1940s (Folder 10: 5)
      Photocopy.
    - Civilian POWs, 1943-1944 (Folder 10: 6)
    - Deceased POWs buried at Yokohama War Cemetery, Japan, 2001 (Folder 10: 7)
    - Japanese staff in Osaka prisons, circa 1945 (Folder 10: 8)
  - Fukuoka, 1942-1947, 1978-2004 (Boxes 10-11)
    - Camp 1, circa 1945, 2002 (Folder 10: 9-10)
    - Camp 2, circa 1945 (Folder 10: 11)
      Includes photocopy of roster of liberated POWs by nationality and sketch of camp.
    - Camp 3, 1942-2004 (Folder 10: 12-15)
    - Camps 4 and 5, 1945, undated (Folder 10: 16-17)
    - Camp 6-D, circa 1945-2003 (Folder 10: 18-21)
      Includes photocopied excerpts from the diary of Jim MacIntosh and typed drafts for publishing. Also includes correspondence with Joan MacIntosh and enclosed clippings.